Jian(Alex) Wang



I am a motivated ICT professional who has ever worked for over ten years, with the expertise of java&python development, both front-end and back-end, software testing(TDD-junit, cucumber, BDD- selenium), continuous integration and delivery. I also have rich experiences and broad knowledge of Object-Oriented Programming, design pattern, as well as cloud computing and machine learning, along with solid skills of Elasticsearch, database(Oracle, MySql)

As a system designer: according to the diverse demands, choose suitable technologies, and set up system framework, then design the architectures, including database, application frameworks, prototype

As a system developer and tester: familiar with SDLC, develop safe and effective code in financial, mechanical systems, such as CRM system for Nepal telecom, IPTV for Italy media, refactor project structures. And use Junit, cucumber&selenium to validate functions

As a system maintainer&optimizator: set up developing&delivery environment, manage& parameterize&optimize delivery system

I am also an active communicator with excellent teamwork and analytical skills used to get the effect in succeeding in a high-pressure situation.

SKILLS

Front-end: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Ajax, JQuery, Backbone, AngularJS, XML, Json

Back-end: Spring, Springboot, SpringMVC, hibernate, JPA, Mybatis, JDBC, Struts, Shiro, WSDL, Swing,

Rest&SOAP NodeJS

Database: Oracle, Mysql, MangoDB, SQlite, Sql server

MQ&distributing system: MQTT, Kafka, Hbase, Hadoop

Search engine: Lucene, ElasticSearch, such as splitting words and optimization of the index building

Python: spiders, machine learning, Django

Test skills: write test cases, findbugs, PDM, TDD, Junit, CUCUMBER and BDD, Selenium, Behave, testRail, Mockito, Stub

Servers: Tomcat, Jboss, Weblogic, IIS, Redis, Nginx, FTP, Image, Apache, Docker, Kubernetes

Design: Powerdesign, Axure RP, UML, Dia

Control: SVN, Git, Jira, Ant, Maven, grunt, Jenkins, Bitbucket, Swagger

Methodology: Agile-Scrum

System: Linux, Linux kernel, windows, a deep research in Linux kernel

IDE: eclipse, plugins, IDEA, Anaconda, webstorm

Android: 3Y+ experiences

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/alex-wang-63237b39/

Github:https://github.com/swoec

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software developer XM developments 08/2018- Auckland

XM developments is a company working on e-commerce system and online stores

The e-commerce platform is based on Java8, Jpa, spring-boot, Elasticsearch, Redis, test using behave, cucumber, Junit, Testrail, Git, Bitbucket, as well as Docker, Kubernetes.

- -> Added new features to user groups: add new columns to the database(flyaway), upgrade models, and relative functions. Write the test case and test the new features(behave in python and Junit)
- -> Labels setting block: designed the label setting tables, designed the Rest APIs, developed all the functions(service, JPA, flyway), function test(behave in python), JUnit test
- -> Junit test and Functional test
- -> Designed database
- -> Designed Rest APIs
- -> Code Review
- -> Code refactoring
 - complete all the functions and Rest APIs, add new features added to the system

Team Leader & architect senior engineer Ligoo New Resource Co, LTD 02/2016-03/2018 Hefei

Ligoo New Resource is the second largest company building BMS for the electric vehicle as well as diverse services in China.

- -> Designed web Framework(Spring framework)
- -> Developed upgrade system by using message queue(MQTT)
- -> Maintained the platform and delivery servers(Ubuntu)
- -> Analysis the data by using python
- -> Designed and built the development environment and architecture
- -> Implemented core business services
- -> Leaded the development of the online platform
- -> Code review
- -> Designed and developed components(Front-end & Back-end)
- -> Addressed and fixed bugs
- -> Cooperated with test&operation engineers to optimize business services
- -> Developed an Android APP for a logistics system
- -> Developed a search engine by using Elasticsearch
- -> Developed a pipeline by using Kafka
- -> Developed spiders to grab data from Internet with Python
- -> Junit Test, Functional Test, Driving Test
- -> Requirements analysis
- Saved a lot of money(at least 2 M dollars every year) to maintain numerous users and respond quickly to users complaints.
- Won more attention and users as the system can help our customers to monitor their vehicles' status and get the vehicle's situation even details, as well as to know the warnings and potential risks
- Successful to support 30 times growth a years.

Senior Software engineer Aisainfo-inc Global Delivery Service 06/2014—01/2016 Nanjing

one of largest CRM software supplier in the world (NASDAQ: ASIA)

- -> Developed functions for Nepal Telecoms, such as balance system, booking system, clients Package system (Front-end & Back-end)
- -> Clarified meta-data and optimized the system structure(Oracle)
- -> Developed plug-ins

- -> Reacted with web interfaces
- -> Fixed bugs and maintained the system
- -> Developed workflows
- -> Junit Test
- Support diverse demands from the users
 Continuous integration and delivery when whatever happens(even a big earthquake)

Senior Software engineer CITIC Department of venture Control 06/2012-06/2014 Nanjing

CITIC corp is the largest financial company in China and top 500 companies in the world.

- -> Designed customized blocks
- -> Developed features for Audit platform(Front-end & Back-end)
- -> Data transfering
- -> Junit and functional test
- -> Integration Test and Delivery
- -> Developed APPs for Bank in Android
- Improve the service quality 200%

 Better resource relocation
 Saving money as more as 20 thousand dollars every year for every branch(more than 500 branches)

Architect Compal R&D center

The second-largest contract laptop manufacturer in the world, also top 500 companies in the world, headquarters is in Taipei, Taiwan, with offices in the People's Republic of China, South Korea, the United Kingdom and the United States

- -> Refactored our android systems
- -> Designed system structure
- -> Developed new features
- -> Interacted with external web interfaces
- -> Designed and Developed web interfaces
- -> Developed a search engine(Lucene)
- Codes became the assets

Senior. Software Engineer ZTE

06/2008-05/2010 Nanjing

06/2010-2012 Nanjing

The fourth Largest mobile equipment manufacturer in the world, with offices in 180 countries.

- -> Mainly developed fac&fas, using multi-thread, and IPC, message-queue, pre-read for cloud storage system
- -> Tested and analyzed the bugs
- -> Optimized the system
- -> Wrote reports to compare our product with several other cloud products
- Sold billions of US dollars every year
- Supplies services for Italy telecom, Vietnam telecom, China Telecom, and many other countries.

Software Engineer

Inspur

06/2006-06/2008 Nanjing

- one of the largest solution provider in the world
- -> Developed the core block for SIP(Java Web project)
- -> Designed and Developed new layers for map(Java Swing)
- -> Developed super-large search trees(more than 100,000 points)
- -> Developed themes and search functions by using swing
- -> Junit and Functional test
- -> Code review
- -> Fixed bugs
- 12600 times faster by using multithread to get massive data

EDUCATION —				
Computer Science	_		IBM DB2 International Certified (2006)	
REFERENCES -				

REFERENCES ARE AVAILABLE ON REQUEST